Literatura de Cordel collection, 1918-1995
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Series 3: Profane Tales., 1918-1995.
  - Title: Curumbá Author: Dr. Mangerona Assú Publisher: Supplemento da Guajarina Place: Pará., 1930. (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Title: Capitão Assis de Vasconcellos o heróe da Revolta de 1924 Author: Arinos de Belem Publisher: Supplemento da Guajarina Place: Belem, Pará., Novembro 1930. (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Title: A cadeira electrica, a execução de Vanzetti, Sacco e Madeiros Author: Arinos de Belem Illustrator: unsigned Publisher: Guajarina Place: Belem, Pará., 1900s. (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Title: O cortiço e o cabaré Author: Aleixo Leite Filho Illustrator: signed DILA Publisher: unknown., after 1950. (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Title: Ex-Casa Detenção hoje Casa de Cultura Author: Delarme Monteiro Silva Illustrator: signed MS Publisher: unknown Other: acrostic, DELARME., after 1950. (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Title: O casamento de cheiroso o bode vereador Author: Delarme Monteiro Silva Illustrator: unsigned Publisher: Tip. da Folhetaria Pontes Place: Guarabira, PB., after 1950. (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Title: O retrato do amor Author: José Camilo da Silva Illustrator: unsigned Publisher: Tipografia Pontes Place: Guarabira, PB., after 1950. (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Title: Remédios caseiros rimados cordel Author: Julio J. Carvalho Illustrator: unsigned Publisher: unknown., 1982. (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Title: Riqueza de sertanejo é chão molhado Author: José Francisco Borges Illustrator: signed J.BORGES Publisher: unknown., after 1950. (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Title: A Beata Santa, ou, O falso Cristo Author: Manoel d'Almeida Filho Illustrator: unsigned Publisher: unknown Place: Maceió, Alagoas., 1900s. (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Title: Brasilia rainha do planalto Author: Elias Alves de Carvalho Publisher: unknown Place: Petrópolis, Rio de Janeiro., after 1950. (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Title: O boi assassino, ou, O monstro de baixa grande Author: Franklin Maxado Nordestino Illustrator: signed Amado F. Silva Publisher: F. M. Nordestino Place: Bahia Other: acrostic, MAXADO., setembro de 1979. (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Title: O cabeça chata que virou todo mundo Author: Franklin Maxado Nordestino Illustrator: signed but illegible Publisher: F. M. Nordestino Place: São Paulo Other: acrostic, MAXADO., março de 1980. (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Title: O cordel do cordel Author: Franklin Maxado Nordestino Illustrator: signed F. MAXADO Publisher: F. M. Nordestino Place: São Paulo Other: acrostic, MAXADO., outubro de 1982. (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Title: Corinthians não é mais aquêle do sapo cururu Author: Franklin Maxado Nordestino Illustrator: signed M Publisher: F. M. Nordestino Place: São Paulo Other: acrostic, MAXADO., outubro de 1977. (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Title: Como ser puxa-saco e vencer na vida atual Author: Franklin Maxado Nordestino Illustrator: signed MAXADO Publisher: F. M. Nordestino Place: São Paulo Other: 2a edição, acrostic, MAXADO., fevereiro de 1980. (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Title: O conto da aposentadoria, ou, O trabalhador já descontou o que devia ter pago ao INPS Author: Franklin Maxado Nordestino Illustrator: signed F.MAXADO Publisher: F. M. Nordestino Place: São Paulo Other: acrostic, MAXADO., agosto de 1981. (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Title: O medo acabou, PMDB neles, é hora de mudar, vote certo em Bartolomeu Cadete Vereador Olinda Author: Bartolomeu Cadete Illustrator: unsigned Publisher: unknown Place: Olinda., 1982. (Box 14, Folder 3)
    Sample ballot on rear wrapper.
  - Title: Antífona Author: Valeriano Felix dos Santos Publisher: unknown Place: Bahia, Brasil., 1900s. (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Title: O julgamento do major do escândalo da mandioca Author: Juca Secundino Publisher: unknown Place: Recife., 1900s. (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Title: Jerônimo o grande herói do sertão Author: Caetano Cosme da Silva Publisher: João José da Silva Place: Recife, PE Other: acrostic, CAETANO., 1900s. (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Title: A tremenda briga de Lampião com Sabino Author: Apolonio Alves dos Santos Illustrator: signed Ciro Publisher: Tipografia da Folhetaria Pontes Place: Guarabira, Pb.., after 1950. (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Title: O trabalhador, A onça mais o macaco Recording: Altimar de Alencar Pimentel Transciption: Maria José da Silva Figueiredo Publisher: Núcleo de Pesquisa e Documentação da Cultura Popula, Universidade Federal da Paraíba Place: João Pessoa, Pb.., Novembro 1980. (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Title: Tubiba o desordeiro Author: Trovador Catinguiba Illustrator: unsigned Publisher: Rodolfo Coelho Cavalcante Place: Salvador, Bahia., ca. 1973. (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Title: A tanajura que caiu no Rio das Velhas Author: Demôstenes de Oliveira Illustrator: signed MS Publisher: unknown., after 1950. (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Title: História da moça que foi enterrada viva, ou, A infeliz Sofia Author: João Martins de Athayde Illustrator: unsigned Publisher: Tip. São Francisco Place: Juazeiro do Norte, Ceará., 31/8/53. (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Title: O terror dos cangaceiros da Paraíba do Norte Author: João Severo da Silva Illustrator: unsigned Publisher: Universidade Federal de Pernambuco Place: Pernambuco Other: acrostic, J.SEVERO., after 1950. (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Title: Incêndio e destruição do mercado público de Juazeiro do Norte, Ce. Author: Abraão Batista Illustrator: signed ABB Publisher: A. Batista Place: Juazeiro do Norte Other: 2a edição., 16/12/74. (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Title: Olinda agradece Author: Maria Guiomar Galvão Coelho Leal Publisher: unknown Place: Olinda, Pernambuco., 1983. (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Title: O homem macaco, ou, O lubishomem do cabo Author: José Soares Publisher: unknown Place: Recife., 1900s. (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Title: O jeca na praça Author: José Soares Illustrator: unsigned Publisher: José Bernardo da Silva Ltda. Place: Juazeiro., 20/06/75. (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Title: A historia de Kleber Costa, Baiano com B maiusculo Author: Toni de Lima Illustrator: unsigned Publisher: unknown., after 1950. (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Title: O cachorro dos mortos Author: Leandro Gomes de Barros Illustrator: unsigned Publisher: Editora Luzeiro Limitada Place: São Paulo Other: acrostic, LEANDRO., after 1950. (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Title: A briga de dois matutos por causa de um jumento Author: Enéias Tavares dos Santos Illustrator: unsigned Publisher: Editora Luzeiro Limitada Place: São Paulo., 1980. (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Title: A guerra dos palmares Author: Bule Bule da Bahia, Antonio Ribeiro de Conceição Illustrator: Manuel Victor Publisher: Folheteria de Cordel Maxado Nordestino Place: São Paulo Other: 2a edição., ca. 1983. (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Title: Guerra de Canudos Author: Raimundo Santa Helena Illustrator: signed Santa Helena Publisher: R. S. Helena Place: Rio de Janeiro., 1981. (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Title: Gilberto Santana é o nosso candidato Author: José Francisco da Silva Publisher: unknown., after 1970. (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Title: A queda do SKYLAB e o medo do pessoal Author: Antonio P. de Souza Illustrator: unsigned Publisher: Folhetaria Estrela do Oriente Place: Campina Grande, Paraíba., after 1950. (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Title: A história dos guerreiros de Gurarapes Author: Diniz Vitorino Ferreira Illustrator: signed JCL Publisher: unknown., after 1950. (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Title: Vestibular do fera pobre Author: Gil Oliveira Illustrator: signed R.S. Publisher: Tipografia Casa das Crianças Place: Olinda, Pernambuco., 1985. (Box 14, Folder 4)
    Word bubble in title illustration reads: "N.S. dos chutes ajudai-me".
  - Title: Saudades do sertão Author: José Soares Illustrator: signed J.BORGES Publisher: Folhetaria Borges Place: Bezerros, PE. Other: acrostic, JOSESOARES., after 1950. (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Title: Os sofrimentos dos pobres que pagam o INPS Author: Apolônio Alves dos Santos Illustrator: unsigned Publisher: Tip. Pontes Place: Guarabira, PE. Other: acrostic, AALVES., after 1950. (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Title: Sport Campeão setenta e sete, ou, Sport vinte e uma vez campeão Author: unknown Illustrator: unsigned Publisher: unknown., ca. 1977. (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Title: O valente cobra choca na pega do lubishome Author: Manoel Caboclo e Silva Illustrator: signed AMS Publisher: M. C. e Silva Place: Juazeiro do Norte., 02/01/82. (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Title: É triste o homem cair nas garras do alcoolismo Author: Severino Cesário da Silva Illustrator: signed João Publisher: Fundação Casa das Crianças de Olinda Place: Olinda Other: acrostic, CESARIO., after 1950. (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Title: O terror do banditismo e o defensor da honra sertaneja Author: Manoel Camilo dos Santos Illustrator: signed ARIEL Publisher: A "Estrella" da Poesia Other: acrostic, MANOEL CAMILO., after 1960. (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Title: Três séculos de liberdade Author: Miriam Yasbeck Asfora Illustrator: signed JCL Publisher: Imprensa Universitária da Universidade Federal Rural de Pernambuco Place: Pernambuco., after 1950. (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Title: O tabaréu que perdeu a mulher na estação rodoviária Author: Edmundo Matos Nascimento Illustrator: signed MINELVINO Publisher: unknown Place: Salvador, Bahia Other: acrostic, EDMUNDO., 1980. (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Title: Te cuida mulher! Author: Sabilinha Illustrator: signed Sônia Castro 80 Publisher: Movimento Feminino do P.M.D.B. Place: Salvador, Bahia., 1980. (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Title: O trator e o tratorista Author: Enéias Tavares dos Santos Illustrator: signed ETE Publisher: Seção de Aperfeiçoamento Profissional e Treinamento da COONE, SECOM-COONE Place: Maceió, Al.., after 1950. (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Title: Senhô Ferreira e o negro furacão Author: José Cavalcanti e Ferreira Dila Publisher: Gráfica Sabaó Place: Caruaru, Pe Other: acrostic, JCFDILA., after 1950. (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Title: Saci e bicho folharaz no reino da bicharada Author: Franklin Maxado Nordestino Illustrator: signed MAXADO Publisher: F. M. Nordestino Place: São Paulo Other: acrostic, MAXADO., janeiro de 1977. (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Title: O encontro de Lampião com Dioguinho Author: Antônio Teodoro dos Santos Illustrator: signed Mariano Publisher: Editora Luzeiro Limitada Place: São Paulo., 1960. (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Title: Os cabras de Lampião Author: Manoel d'Almeida Filho Illustrator: unsigned Publisher: Luzeiro Editora Limitada Place: São Paulo., 1966. (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Title: História do cangaceiro João Serra Negra Author: Minelvino Francisco Silva Illustrator: unsigned Publisher: Tip São Francisco Other: 2o Volume., 1900s. (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Title: O herói de Mossoró e o Cel. Cascavel ou Janduí e Lindalva Author: Gerson Araújo de Lucena Illustrator: signed Lucena Pintor 1967 Publisher: G. A. de Lucena Place: Campina Grande, Paraíba Other: 2o Volume, acrostic ARAUJO LUCENA., 18/6/1977. (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Title: Quelé e Lampião Author: José Cavalcanti e Ferreira Dila Illustrator: signed AUTOR DILA Publisher: Sabaó Folheto Place: Caruaru, Pe. Other: acrostic JCFDILA., after 1950. (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Title: Queremos Diretas Já! Para Todos Brasileiros Author: Leonardo Publisher: Amigos da Poesia Popular Ex-Comitê Bancário Pro-Miguel Arraes., ca. 1984. (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Title: O rapaz que apanhou 3 surras para aprender a namorar Author: Manoel Caboclo e Silva Illustrator: unsigned Publisher: M. C. e Silva., after 1950. (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Title: O bataclam moderno, O azar na casa do funileiro Author: José Bernardo da Silva Illustrator: unsigned Publisher: Tip. São Francisco Place: Juazeiro do Norte, Ce.., 1900s. (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Title: Faleceu Mané Garrincha o fabicante de Joãos Author: Gonçalo Ferreira da Silva Illustrator: signed MS Publisher: unknown., ca. 1983. (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Title: A embolada do meu bodó Author: Antonio Almeida da Silva Illustrator: unsigned Publisher: Benedito Antonio de Matos., 1900s. (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Title: Explosão em Garanhuns Author: Valdeck de Garanhuns Publisher: unknown., ca. 1980. (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Title: Eu? Author: Rui Mattos Publisher: unknown., after 1950. (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Title: Endemoniado castrou um menino de 11 anos em Juazeiro do Norte Author: Abraão Batista Illustrator: signed ABB Publisher: A. Batista Place: Recife., 19/dezembro/1975. (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Title: O enbalo do nautico, hexa campeão Author: Luiz Gonzaga de Lima Illustrator: signed J.BORGES Publisher: L. G. de Lima Place: Garanhuns, PE., 19/9/1975. (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Title: Ecos da revolução de 31 de março Author: Homero de Rêgo Barros Publisher: L. G. de Lima Place: Recife., 1965. (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Title: O encontro do colono, com o moço garimpeiro Author: Marcelino Pereira de Aguiar Illustrator: signed but illegible Publisher: unknown., after 1950. (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Title: É um pouco de tudo da puizia popular Author: Manoel Florentino Duarte Publisher: unknown., 1900s. (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Title: Encontro dos presidenciáveis no largo da carioca no Rio de Janeiro Author: Abraão Batista Illustrator: signed ABB Publisher: A. Batista Place: Juazeiro do Norte., 1984. (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Title: Exaltação ao povo capixaba e ao estado do Espírito Santo Author: Rodolfo Coelho Cavalcante Illustrator: signed JRS Publisher: R. C. Cavalcante Place: Salvador, Bahia., 1981. (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Title: A enchente do distrito poço Author: Olímpio Bento de Figueredo Illustrator: unsigned Publisher: unknown Place: Brejo-Santo, Ceará., 29/abril/1979. (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Title: Os estudantes com fome sem achar o que comer Author: Valdélia Barros Pereira Illustrator: unsigned Publisher: unknown Place: Campina Grande., 23/9/1977. (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Title: Echos da patria, Torpedeamento do vapor Macau, A guerra, Canto de Guerra Author: Leandro Gomes de Barros Illustrator: unsigned Publisher: A Editora Place: Recife., 1900s. (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Title: A epopéa do Amazonas Author: Dr. Mangerona Assú Publisher: Guajarina, A Editora Place: Pará., 1924. (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Title: A eleição dos cornos Author: Hagarra Aminha Illustrator: signed MS Publisher: unknown., after 1950. (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Title: A rainha do cangaço Author: Apolônio Alves dos Santos Illustrator: signed JCL Publisher: Tip. Pontes Place: Guarabira, Paraíba Other: acrostic, AALVES., 14/9/81. (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Title: A embolada da velha chica Author: Francisco Sales Arêda Illustrator: signed J.BORGES Publisher: unknown., after 1950. (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Title: A escrava Isaura, a jovem sofredora Author: Apolônio Alves dos Santos Publisher: Manoel Caboclo e Silva Other: acrostic, AALVES., 02/01/81. (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Title: Encontro de Lampião com Zé Guará, um valente cangaceiro do E. da Bahia Author: Severino Cesário da Silva Illustrator: signed MS Publisher: unknown Place: Recife., 24 de janeiro 1980. (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Title: O encontro de Rodolfo Cavalcante com Lampião Virgulino Author: Severino Cesário da Silva Illustrator: unsigned Publisher: R. C. Cavalcante Place: Salvador, Bahia., novembro de 1973. (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Title: O encontro de Urutú com Dioguinho, o valentão do sul do Brasil Author: João Antonio de Barros Illustrator: signed J.BARROS Publisher: Tipografia da Folhetaria Pontes Place: Guarabira, Paraíba Other: acrostic, JOTABARROS., after 1950. (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Title: O encontro de Manoel Tiroteio com Sabino Peixerada Author: Expedito F. Silva Illustrator: signed Ciro Publisher: Gráfica e Editora "GED" Ltda. Place: Rio de Janeiro Other: acrostic, EFSILVA., after 1960. (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Title: Encontro de João Faisca com Francisco Pinga Fogo Author: Apolônio Alves dos Santos Illustrator: signed MS Publisher: Tip. Pontes Place: Guarabira, Pb. Other: acrostic, AALVES., after 1950. (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Title: As eleições vem aí Author: Apolônio Alves dos Santos Illustrator: signed MS Publisher: Tip. Pontes Place: Guarabira, Pb.., 6/4/82. (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Title: Eu também sou presidenciável Author: Franklin Maxado Nordestino Publisher: F. M. Nordestino Place: São Paulo Other: acrostic, MAXADO., junho de 1983. (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Title: A eleição dos cornos Author: H. Raminha Illustrator: signed J.BORGES Publisher: unknown., after 1950. (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Title: As anedotas de Quintino Cunha Author: João Batista Serra Illustrator: signed A.M.S. Publisher: Benedito Antônio de Matos Place: Fortaleza, Ce.., after 1950. (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Title: ABC do Dr. Carlos Alberto Azevedo, Embaixador da Literatura de Cordel na Europa, residente na Alemanha Author: José Severino Cristóvão e Maria do Carmo Cristóvão Publisher: unknown Place: Caruaru, PE.., after 1960. (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Title: O encontro de Antonio Silvino com o valente Nicácio na Vila de Trapiá Author: Severino Cesário Illustrator: signed DILA Publisher: unknown Place: Departamento de Extenção Cultural da Pro-Reitoria para Assuntos Comuniários da Universidade Federal de Pernambuco Other: acrostic, CESARIO., after 1950. (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Title: O encontro do rapaz que virou bode com a moça que virou cabra Author: H. Romeu Illustrator: unsigned Publisher: unknown Other: acrostic, H.ROMEU., 1900s. (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Title: Epopéia das secas Author: Raimundo Santa Helena Publisher: R. S. Helena Place: Rio de Janeiro., 7/9/1983. (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Title: João Claudino Fernandes, bom filho, bom esposo, bom pai e bom amigo Author: Rodolfo Coelho Cavalcante Illustrator: signed JRS Publisher: R. C. Cavalcante Place: Bahia., 1981. (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Title: Antônio Silvino, vida, crimes e julgamento Author: Francisco das Chagas Batista Illustrator: signed GLEN Publisher: Luzeiro Editora Limitada Place: São Paulo., after 1950. (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Title: Resumo biográfico de José Bernardo da Silva Author: Expedito Sebastião da Silva Illustrator: Stênio Diniz Publisher: unknown., after 1972. (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Title: Carybé o artista que se tornou baiano pela lei, pela arte e pelo povo Author: Rodolfo Coehlo Cavalcante Publisher: Fundação Cultural do Estado da Bahia Coordenação de Bibliotecas Other: acrostic, CARIBÉ., after 1960. (Box 15, Folder 1)
    Note on page 8 cites Jorge Amado's book "Bahia de todos os santos" as inspiration for the poem.
  - Title: Carta do povo brasileiro pela constituinte para reconstruir já Author: Raimundo Silva e Franklin Maxado Nordestino Publisher: unknown Place: São Paulo., março 1985. (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Title: Conselhos aos eletricistas Author: Enéas Tavares dos Santos Illustrator: signed ETS Publisher: SECOM-COONE Place: Maceió, Al. Other: acrostic, ENÉIAS., after 1960. (Box 15, Folder 1)
    Note on rear wrapper: Programa Nacional de Melhoramento da Cana-de-Acucar Coordenadoria Regional Nordeste.
  - Title: A historia do I Congresso Nacional de Literatura de Cordel no Rio de Janeiro Author: Adalberto Almeida Santos Publisher: Ordem Brasileira dos Poetas da Literatura de Cordel Place: Salvador Other: acrostic, BSANTOS., 14 de março de 1980. (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Title: Horóscopo das bichas Author: Franklin Maxado Illustrator: signed MAXADO Publisher: Gráfica e Editora "GED" Ltda. Place: Rio de Janeiro Other: 2a edição; acrostic, MAXADO., junho de 1977. (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Title: A construção do partido de todos trabalhadores, Trabalhador vota em seu partido Author: Crispiano Neto Illustrator: signed Marcilio Publisher: Escola Dom Bosco de Artes e Ofícios Place: Recife, PE., 1980's. (Box 15, Folder 1)
    Sample voting ballot on rear wrapper.
  - Title: Camponeses Unidos, lutam por seus direitos Author: unknown Illustrator: unsigned Publisher: Sindicatos e FETAPE., 1980. (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Title: Cordel do Recife Author: Homero do Rêgo Barros Publisher: unknown Place: Recife Other: acrostic, HOMERO., janeiro 1982. (Box 15, Folder 1)
    Author's inscription on page 1.
  - Title: O grupo que aproveita a musica do nosso povo Author: Maxado Nordestino Publisher: unknown Place: São Paulo Other: acrostic, MAXADO., after 1960. (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Title: Drummond Author: Raimundo Santa Helena Illustrator: signed Waltor Publisher: R. S. Helena Place: Rio de Janeiro., 7/10/1984. (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Title: A bravura do Sargento Max Wolff Filho na Segunda Guerra Mundial Author: Romildo Luiz dos Santos Publisher: unknown., after 1950. (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Title: A justiça social é ensino público e gratuito Author: Crispiniano Neto Publisher: unknown Place: Campina Grande., julho 82. (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Title: O Zeppelin vem ahi! Author: Arinos de Belem Publisher: Supplemento da Guajarina Place: Belém, Pará., ca. 1920s. (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Title: Aposentadoria dos velhos Author: Alberto Porfirio Publisher: unknown., after 1950. (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Title: Porque voto em Nilo Coelho Author: Manoel Quixabeira Publisher: unknown Place: Caruarú, Pernambuco., 1978. (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Title: A poeira tem memória Miguel Arraes Author: Delarme Monteiro Publisher: unknown Other: acrostic, DELARME., ca. 1982. (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Title: O pinto pelado Author: João Ferreira de Lima Publisher: unknown., 1900s. (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Title: Paço imperial Author: Raimundo Santa Helena Publisher: R. S. Helena Place: Rio de Janeiro., 14/3/1985. (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Title: O pistoleiro da serra na caverna da morte Author: José Pedro Pontual Illustrator: unsigned Publisher: Edson Pinto., after 1950. (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Title: Zé Côco do Riachão Author: Téo Azevedo Illustrator: Zé Chorró, M. Claros Publisher: unknown., after 1950. (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Title: O heroismo de um sertanejo Author: João Firmino Cabral Illustrator: signed J.BORGES Publisher: Folhetaria Borges Other: acrostic, FIRMINO., after 1950. (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Title: O homem que fez profissão da mentira e passou a crença a seu filho de 6 anos de idade Author: José da Rocha Publisher: unknown., 1900s. (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Title: História do macaco guerreiro e o Valente Sebastião Author: Josias Novo de Almeida Publisher: Museu Théo Brandão, UFAL Place: Maceió, Al. Other: acrostic, JOSIAS., 1980. (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Title: O homem da "gaia" mole Author: João Severo da Silva Illustrator: unsigned Publisher: Folhetaria São João Place: Bayeux, Pb. Other: acrostic, J.SEVERO., after 1950. (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Title: Literatura de cordel, antologia Author: Camillo Calazans de Magalhães and others Publisher: Banco do Nordeste do Brasil S.A.., after 1950. (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Title: Os direitos da criança Author: José Vicente Illustrator: signed but illegible Publisher: Editora Vozes Place: Petrópolis, RJ., 16 de março de 1979. (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Title: Casa do sertão Author: João Crispim Ramos Illustrator: unsigned Publisher: Lions Clube de Feira de Santana Place: Santana, Bahia Other: acrostic, J.C.RAMOS., 1978. (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Title: Quem é fã de Frank Sinatra desconhece a grandeza dos poetas e artistas do Brasil Author: Antonio Lucena do Mossoró Illustrator: unsigned Publisher: Folha do Subúrbio Gráfica e Editora Ltda. Place: Camaçari, Bahia., after 1950. (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Title: A dura vida do motorista Author: José Caetano da Silva Illustrator: unsigned Publisher: Gutemberg Liberato de Andrade Collection: Caatinga Cearense No 1., 20/09/82. (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Title: Embolada do galo do mar Author: José Domingos de Araujo Illustrator: unsigned Publisher: José Joavilim Silva Place: Caruaru, Pernambuco., 1900s. (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Title: O homem que nasceu prá ser chifrudo e as 3 mulheres galheiras Author: O Carioca Illustrator: signed J.BORGES Publisher: unknown., after 1950. (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Title: O homem que nasceu prá ser chifrudo e as 3 mulheres galheiras Author: O Carioca Illustrator: signed JCL Publisher: A Voz da Poesia Nordestina., after 1950. (Box 15, Folder 1)